Lot Smith papers, 1854-1890
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Lot Smith papers, 1854-1890
AZ 186
Smith, Lot, 1830-1892
Collection consists of correspondence, legal papers, biographical and family materials relating to Lot Smith. Smith was a Mormon soldier and colonist, and leader of the mission to settle the Little Colorado River area in northern Arizona beginning in 1876.
.2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Library Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
Originals are restricted. Users are required to use photocopies of the collection.
Biographical Note
Smith was a Mormon soldier and colonist, and leader of the mission to settle the Little Colorado River area in northern Arizona beginning in 1876.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series:
I. Correspondence, 1857-1890
II. Legal documents, 1855-1888
III. Miscellaneous, 1878-1962
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists of correspondence, legal papers, biographical and family materials. Correspondence consists chiefly of letters to Lot Smith, while president of the Little Colorado Stake, from Brigham Young, Wilford Woodruff, and other officials of the Mormon Church regarding colonization in Arizona at Sunset Crossing on the Little Colorado River. Also included are correspondence and commissions relating to Smith's earlier military service; tithing receipts; minutes of a 1889 Mormon High Council meeting concerning Smith; certificates of election to Utah Territorial legislative assemblies; and a 1962 address list of Smith's descendants.
Access Terms
Young, Brigham, 1801-1877 -- Correspondence
Woodruff, Wilford, 1807-1898 -- Correspondence
Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints -- Zion Stake -- Little Colorado
Mormons -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Mormon church -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Church buildings -- Arizona -- History
Joseph City Region (Ariz.) -- History -- Sources
Correspondence
Minutes
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1857-1890
  - Wells to Lot Smith. October 17, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clark to Lot Smith. September 29, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Young, Kimball, and Wells to Lot Smith. April 30, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Assistant Adjutant General H.B. Clawson to Lot Smith. July 15, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Assistant Adjutant General H.B. Clawson to Lot Smith. May 21, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Colonel R.T. Burton to Lot Smith. April 28, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Winder to Lot Smith. May 11, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Leiutenant General Daniel H. Wells to Lot Smith. May 23, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Colonel R.T. Burton to Lot Smith. June 12, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. May 20, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. March 4, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. April 26, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. May 14, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lot Smith to Brigham Young. July 7, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. July 14, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith, Lake, Ballinger, Allen, and the brethren encamped on the Little Colorado. July 15, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. July 29, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith and other presidents of companies, Little Colorado River. August 7, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith and other presidents of companies, Little Colorado River. September, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. November 25, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young, J.W. Young, Erastus Snow, and Brigham Young Jr. to Lot Smith, Ballanger, Lake, and Allen. St George, Utah. January 10, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. Sunset Crossing. June 28, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Elder George Lake. July 13, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Taylor to Lot Smith. October 23, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Taylor to Lot Smith. April 14, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Taylor to Lot Smith. August 20, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Taylor to presidents of the various branches of Zion. August 22, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Taylor to Lot Smith. November 27, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - McKenzie to Lot Smith. Tithing orders. December 4, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith. February 29, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Taylor to Lot Smith. August 14, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lot Smith to John Taylor. March 31, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. April 3, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. April 12, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. April 21, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. May 12, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. June 19 ,1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. September 15, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. December 14, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. January 27, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to all the saints. January 27, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lot Smith to John Taylor (incomplete). February, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John W. Young to Lot Smith. April 26, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. January 16, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. January 31, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John W. Young to Smith. August 3, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brigham Young Jr. to Lot Smith. October 17, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. October 23, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. November 10, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. November 28, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. December 7, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. March 23, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. April 17, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. November 8, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. February 26, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Taylor. April 10, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Lot Smith. April 15, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woodruff to Taylor. April 18, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - T.W. Brookbank to Lot Smith. October 3, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Daniel Taylor to Lot Smith. July 7, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lot Smith to Woodruff. March 11, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brigham Young to Lot Smith, No Date (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Latter fragment (sender and recepient unknown). No Date (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Legal Documents, 1855-1888
  - Lot Smith, Captain's comission, Utah Territorial Militia. 1855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lot Smith, certificate of membership in Deseret Agricultural and Manufacturing Society. January, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lot Smith, certificate of election as Utah legislative representative. October 10, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Power of attorney, William Loveland to J. Charles Remington. April 24, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lot Smith, Brigadier General's commission, Utah Territorial Militia. February 26, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lot Smith, certificate of election as member of council of Utah legislature. December 20, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lot Smith, receipt for purchase of a horse. January 15, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lot Smith and Martin Sanders, receipt for purchase of livestock. June 28, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lot Smith, claim of a survivor of the Mexican War for pension. 1888 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series III: Miscellaneous, 1878-1962
  - Minutes of Mormon high council meeting. A.S. Farnsworth and Lot Smith livestock case. May 31, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Tithing receipts. 1878-1883 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, blessings, biographical materials. 1878-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)